

💌 jean-claude.desrosiers@jclaude.xyz | 🖸 jeanclaude-desrosiers | 🧩 www.jclaude.xyz | 📕 (+1) 438-990-4360 | 😾 DesJC | 🛅 jclaude-des

Profile

Communication Fit to work within a team and with clients; fluent in both english and french

Learning Adept at learning computer science skills and concepts, vert quickly

Hardworking Resolve to produce efficient and applied work

Interested in low-level programming, theoretical computer science, quantum computing, etc. Curiosity

Skills

Programming Fluency with multiple paradigms (object-oriented, declarative, functional, logical, etc.)

System Knowledgeable in low-level (C et MIPS) and machine (VHDL) programming Development Experienced in designing and developing Java desktop applications with Maven

> Web Knowledgeable in front-end (Bootstrap, Javascript) and back-end (NodeJS, PHP, .NET) development

Mobile Practical experience developing Android and React. js applications for mobile

Database Efficient in SQL query writing and database design

Linux Knowledgeable at using a Linux operating system and command-line utilities

Education

UdeM (Université de Montréal)

Montreal, Quebec

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept. 2019 - May 2022

- Practical and theoretical problems related to software design and development
- Awarded two scholarships of excellence in the computer science department in 2020 and 2022

Dawson College Montreal, Quebec

DIPLOMA OF COLLEGIAL STUDIES IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept. 2016 - May. 2019

• Rapid Application Development for desktop, web and mobile environments according to industry standards

Work Experience

Desjardins Montreal, Quebec

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER May 2021 - May 2022

- · Maintenance, exploitation and development with applications such as uCMDB, UD, SmartTrack and BigFix in Python and Java
- Use Windows batch scripting to automate jobs and Python for development
- Apply ITSM processes in the ITIL v.4 framework

Desjardins Montreal, Quebec

May 2020 - May 2021

- · Provide technical support for those working in Desjardins caisses
- · Work in a team, along other teams, towards a common goal

Bacon Financial Technologies (Hardbacon)

Longueuil, Quebec Apr. 2019 - May 2019

Sept. 2019 - April 2021

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

VOLUNTEER

IT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

- · Develop and designing (with a team) a mobile application in React for portfolio management and financial counseling
- Meet deadlines for releases of versions matching the marketing campaign

Extracurricular Activity_

Code Club Canada St-Philippe, Quebec

• Develop a series of activities for kids to playfully learn how to code with Scratch and Microbit

- · Build an introductory class on web technologies (HTML/CSS/JS) for adolescents
- · Animate said activities, weekly, in a small group